So in this video, we're going to have a look at the map interface and its subclasses starting with the hash map, right?
So what is the situation where you'd find yourself prefering a map over other interfaces and their subclasses is
When your requirement is to store data in key value pairs and hash map exactly provides you that will just go on and in the collections package again
I'll just create a new class and just call it hash map
Can I call my class as hash map there's a question for you, right?
I can because it would be in my own package and the in-built class that is hash map
It is in the package java.util. No conflicts, but it would be stupid for me to do that. Why? Because
Later on when I'll call methods of the hash map
I'll be left scratching my head because I'll try to find my own class methods
Which are not there so never call it like this although you can
just say working with hash map
So again, we'll just have the main method and then I'll just go on and create a hash map
key value pairs
Separate by comma this time the generic parameters have to be - you can have the keys as integers
Values as your custom class objects. That's coming on for you as well
But you can have it any bit that is your requirement for now. I'll just say that let's have them as integers
Value a strings and then let's say the keys are the IDs values are the names, right?
I'll just call it on your nurse map
and then new hash map
Climate syntax from this time the method change from Ed to put in a map
We have to put method. So I'll just say put it says put in the key and the value. I'll just put it a few times
Let's say we have the key 45 bound to the learner name
That was again for example near and then we have we want to and this is
John
We have one to three for for example bound to the name that is whack and then we have learners are put the ID is
43 and it is bound to the name
Ochman and then we have let's say
21 bound to the name that is this time
Right
So now if we go ahead and print that out you will see I'll just say learners
But you can just use a for loop for each or an enhanced for loop to traverse that as in the previous examples
If we just printed like this, you will see that there is no order to invoice they were stored because like it's counterpart in the said
That is a high said hash map is an unordered
Unsorted collection. Let's verify that with this output
It says we added 45 first but in no order
It just added one two three four with back and then see is equal to because key value
That's why we are in the first place using a map then three one two John
43 smile 45 Neha and four 31 step right there's no order to this in the way we ordered in the way we inserted
Sorry, and this is a hash map working can duplicates be allowed not keys
But values can be duplicate right go and try that as well
But that is how we use a hash name now in which what situation will you prefer using a hash map first things first
When your requirement is to store data and key value pairs the second
A requirement would be that is when you're not concerned with ordering and sorting
This is not an order neither a sorted collection right in that situation go on and use a hash map
But when you are concerned with sorting and you want to store data and key value pairs
Something is coming out for you in the next video